<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Hugo Profile</title>
    <link>https://forrestfwilliams.com/blogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Hugo Profile</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 09:30:02 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://forrestfwilliams.com/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ZRAN</title>
      <link>https://forrestfwilliams.com/blogs/zran/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 09:30:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forrestfwilliams.com/blogs/zran/</guid>
      <description>The Problem Like most forms of data analysis, remote sensing has traditionally operated in a file-first paradigm. In this setup, data is packaged in discrete files or zip archives and these are downloaded/decompressed to a local environment before you begin analyzing the data.
However, with the growth in dataset sizes, the move to cloud-based computing, and new tools like Xarray, the industry is moving towards a dataset-first paradigm. In a dataset-first paradigm we think about grabbing the specific data we want from a global dataset instead of downloading discrete files that contain portions of the dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>https://forrestfwilliams.com/blogs/hello_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 09:30:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forrestfwilliams.com/blogs/hello_world/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! My name is Forrest Williams, and I’m excited to introduce myself to you.
I recently graduated from a New Zealand university with a PhD in geology where I studied landslides, but I now find myself working in the fascinating (and confusing) world of synthetic aperture radar (SAR) remote sensing.
I work at the Alaska Satellite Facility (NASA’s SAR data center), where I am both a scientist and a software developer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
