<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forrest Williams</title>
    <link>https://forrestfwilliams.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Forrest Williams</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 09:30:02 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://forrestfwilliams.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An InSAR Colorsphere</title>
      <link>https://forrestfwilliams.com/blogs/los/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 09:30:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forrestfwilliams.com/blogs/los/</guid>
      <description>Usage Use the Satellite Heading and Grazing Angle sliders to adjust the values for these parameters. The graphs will update, and colorbar below will display the color values for your specified satellite orientation. You can also select presets for Sentinel-1, NISAR, and horizontal/vertical orientations.
The Why When interpreting deformation measurements created using InSAR, it&amp;rsquo;s important to remember that the deformation measured is always along the SAR satellite&amp;rsquo;s line-of-sight. This means that two SAR satellites looking at the same deformation from different orientations will make different measurements of the deformation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZRAN</title>
      <link>https://forrestfwilliams.com/blogs/zran/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 09:30:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forrestfwilliams.com/blogs/zran/</guid>
      <description>The Problem Like most forms of data analysis, remote sensing has traditionally operated in a file-first paradigm. In this setup, data is packaged in discrete files or zip archives and these are downloaded/decompressed to a local environment before you begin analyzing the data.
However, with the growth in dataset sizes, the move to cloud-based computing, and new tools like Xarray, the industry is moving towards a dataset-first paradigm. In a dataset-first paradigm we think about grabbing the specific data we want from a global dataset instead of downloading discrete files that contain portions of the dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>https://forrestfwilliams.com/blogs/hello_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 09:30:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forrestfwilliams.com/blogs/hello_world/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! My name is Forrest Williams, and I’m excited to introduce myself to you.
I recently graduated from a New Zealand university with a PhD in geology where I studied landslides, but I now find myself working in the fascinating (and confusing) world of synthetic aperture radar (SAR) remote sensing.
I work at the Alaska Satellite Facility (NASA’s SAR data center), where I am both a scientist and a software developer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
